<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<log type="releaseNotes">
    <source target="https://7daystodie.com/alpha-17-1-is-out/"/>
<title>Alpha 17.1 Is Out!</title>
Hey Survivalist,

We’ve just released Alpha 17.1 Stable and here are the official releases notes:

To improve stamina players now start with 150 food which is now shown in the hud and menu to communicate you can overeat and not waste food.

When players stamina is between 100 and 150, there are no detrimental stamina effects.

Strength requirements for the Sexual Tyrannosaurus perk have been lowered and we have made the description clear that it does reduce mining stamina costs as well as melee costs. We moved it from the combat perk section to a new section called general strength perks. We’ve reduced the stamina cost of all tools.  We’ve also reduced stone tool stamina penalties.

Water now goes to 150%, and until the water debuff comes on screen at 75% water, you will experience no stamina regeneration penalties.

For builders, we have bolstered XP for harvesting and mining substantially allowing for support roles to keep up with combat and scavenger roles.

If you have problems please visit our Alpha 17.1 Stable Bug Reporting Thread.

We will continue to fix bugs, balance the game, and optimize in 17.2 coming soon.

A17.1 b9
Added

Entityclasses AIPathCostScale (min/max) and set a variety of values for different AI entities
Sleeper 20% bonus to AIPathCostScale
Vehicle manager saves when vehicles are added or removed
Added Cigars to trader wares
Added old cash to laundry and nightstands
AI will do destroy area 60% on a fall after unreachable side path
Traders now sell glue
When the PLY option is checked in the F3 debug screen, the cvar window with a new search box will be displayed on your right hand side. Ideal for searching xp related cvars.
Changed

Optimized catwalk rail metal corner, catwalk rail single, catwalk wedge rail, chair, coffee table
Separated pathing distance cost from break/jump cost and added per path scaling to allow path variations
Increased trader rewards
AI JumpMaxDistance to a random range, set zombie ranges and made heavier zombies jump shorter
Updated several buff descriptions and journal entries to reflect changes
Added a beaker to medical quest loot
Return of the ghosted block preview from A16
Added acid to lab equipment loot
Water and food to show the value of current water and food plus the consumed water and food amounts to be applied
Adjusted max water amounts in progression to reflect the food amounts
Updated chrysanthemum seed icon.
Show the water/food as actual value instead of percent.
Increased dog and wolf health
Death penalty cannot stack on repeated deaths
Increased block upgrade speed of nail gun and claw hammer
A wood pole can be crafted without the table saw
Updated vehicleWheels icon.
Increased amount of old cash found in containers and zombie loot.
ModMeleeStructuralBrace can be installed on bows and has fewer stacking issues
Increased size of snake colliders
Increased harvesting / upgrade XP
Increased AI range to attempt a gap jump
General Strength Perks have their own category.
Perks concerning harvesting, looting or carrying things require lower attribute scores to unlock
Increased the amount of food you can overeat to 50.
Increased stack count of buff magazines
Increased stack number of cash
Allowed 45° rotations on wood/iron bars
Added support for lumberjacks. Wood now sells for a reasonable amount at traders
Player sellback rate improved so selling items to traders is more profitable
Increased drop % of armor mods in loot
Vehicles can be assembled from parts without a perk
Glue requires only 1 bone now instead of 2.
Reduced price of glue it was more expensive than duct tape
Terrain in prefabs is now integrated into the height map and saved into a temporary file dtm_processed.raw on server side
Optimized the way imposter prefab are calculated (less network traffic)
Fixed

Stat Current life does not reset upon death.
Craft timers not being loaded from saved data correctly
AI climb flag not set when temp move
LCB icon is still shown when LCB has been destroyed by another player.
Bedroll compass/map icon was still showing when destroyed by another player when out of chunk.
Crafting timer doesn’t advance properly when the chunk is unloaded
Fuel burn timer showing huge negative value in MP
Silencer does not actually silence all weapons
Tuned water message closer to actual in game effect
Increased quality of items for quest rewards
Vehicle out of world check using different positions for chunk and terrain tests, so vehicles could get killed and removed Kill
Zombies prefer to not path glass blocks
Player backpack can be pushed under the world
Dupe anything in a container.
If a server is restarted shortly after placing a vehicle, the vehicle will disappear
Fixed mismatched reinforced padding icon.
Any block that can be picked up, can be picked up in a lcb protected area.
Relogging on activate marker.
Quests sometimes require moving to corner/center of POI to show Rally Marker.
Wellness achievement updated to use fortitude
Relogging on fresh quest will break trigger area.
Tier5 does not give you a complete quest after requirements are met.
When blocks are placed where sleepers would spawn, they can turn yellow
Replaced cntmrandomloothelper in house_old_mansard with random store crate
Allow harvested decor plants to be scrapped
Weapon bags do not fall when POI’s fall
Clothing change can cause major lag spike/fps drop
Updated mining journal entry
Tree duping issue when hit by vehicles in LCB
Holding F is not mentioned on relevant item descriptions
Open\Close toggle issues with some hatches.
Strong zombies dropped less cash than weak zombies
Item is lost if left on the mouse when closing a container.
Toolbelt items being stuck after use.
Bleeding buff carries over to respawn
Sidewalk terrain will not allow placing blocks on it
Self medicated perk magazine is still in game
Command smoothworldall only working for 4k maps
Corrected more burn times
XBOX controller has not designated button/switch for making air vehicle point down (added controller action 2 to hop)
Fixed distant water not being flat as a client
Wrong stats displayed on some armor mods
Grandpa’s Awesome Sauce is too awesome
Water is not wet enough. Swimming / rain will now cool you down.
GunToolNailgun can use trigger group mods
ModArmorWaterPurifier collides with modArmorHelmetLight
Terrain decoration like trees and resource rocks would sometimes not be placed
Known Issues

Continued b240 savegames may have problems with food/water levels when a replenishing buff was active when game is continued in A17.1, character’s death restores functionality
Some tier 5 dungeons may not complete the clear quests
In some scenarios double swing may still occur
Tool damage localization is different than actual value
RWG: Floating POIs (Minimal occurrence now)
Trader Jen has a deep voice
Trader Rekt is nicer than usual
Charismatic Nature is still in need of improvement, buff works for 5 seconds and 5 seconds it does not
Scrapping items in crafting queue while re-logging may go lost
Re-logging when crafting usable items are in the crafting queue may have negative side effects
Crafting speed bonus and mod slots do not properly apply to workstations after being closed
Clipping into blocks to see through terrain
Vultures play their fly animation when dead for clients
Shotgun driver loses sound on 4×4 after a while
Workstation tools do not refresh the recipe list when the tools are installed
Can use torch and flaming arrows as light underwater
Hitting ESC while generating a map preview will blank screen. Must use CTRL, ALT, DEL to exit game.
RWG preview tool localization
Firearms do a duplicate reload animation after reloading while zoomed (locked in zoom)
Mining helmet light doesn’t show for other players
Client molotovs thrown down from an edge not working as good as Host
Hatches don’t always open on the first try
Player model jumps forward of the player camera when accessing an auto turret inventory
Turrets will not target self when set to do so
Player can consume any consumable while mounted in vehicle but will not get the buff/debuff
Flames don’t move with zombie ragdolls
Resolution does not always save when >1080p options are available
Burning shaft mod flame effect can transfer to other items on the toolbelt
Healing other players with RMB doesn’t work
Self medicated is not working properly. Not being able to purchase perk is intended.
Crashes on Mac for a possible workaround, please look at  https://7daystodie.com/forums/showthread.php?101758-Found-workaround-for-constant-crashes-on-Mac&p=914106#post914106
If connection to server fails, try removing steamnetworking as a disabled function from the serverconfig.xml
White lines may occur on imposter POIs
Some Linux users experience problems
When using REALLY excessive amounts of resources they may vanish in cement mixer’s crafting queue
Loot abundance setting needs another look
Placing a new landclaim may cause the icon to disappear
Some dupes/exploits we are looking into
This entry was posted in News on 01/18/2019 by rhuenink.
</log>